HARUKA HASHIMOTO

CLIENT ACCOUNT MANAGEMENT

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

A key account manager with over 13 years of experience in the automotive industry, working with various stakeholders. Accustomed to working under fast paced environment with the ability to perform well under pressure. Proven talent for managing complex projects and a tact for problem solving. Results driven with a strong sense of accountability in ensuring customer excellence. Now looking for a role in the educational sector to develop further professionally, where current skill set can be utilised.

CONTACT

+44 (0) 7595 122 480

Birmingham, UK

haruka.hashimoto08@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/haruka-h-587b41100

WORK EXPERIENCE

SITE MANAGER (TOYOTA MOTOR MANUFACTURING UK)

PPG Industries (UK) Ltd. / Birmingham / 2020-Current

Overall management of the customer account, maintaining close interactions with the client and ensuring customer satisfaction on various aspects of the business.

- Scored 4/5 for customer satisfaction ratings for quarterly client survey
- Reduced order errors by 10% by improving order checking process
- Coordinated annual PAT testing for all office electrical appliances with a third party vendor, arranging temporary site entry pass and PPE
- Reduced approx. 43% in transportation cost and resources by decreasing test frequencies
- Anticipated urgent customer request, promptly organising production to delivery of 5 products within 5 weeks meeting original customer deadline
- Campaigned to implement the use of plastic IBC for cost saving and quality improving purposes, cultivating a new waste stream with a third party vendor and advising customer on equipment required to accommodate change
- Conducted 1 to 1 quarterly appraisals to encourage growth, ensuring positive and pleasant working culture
- Reconciled account receivables and resolved invoice disputes
- Managed monthly remittance of external vendor contracts of approx.
 €54000/annum, ensuring continuous product supply
- Championed problem investigation with technical teams and authored a report, successfully resolving a customer claim
- Enforced the use of correct PPE in accordance with risk assessments and adherence to health and safety regulations to all team members and visitors
- Negotiated on site vehicle entry and parking permits with a section manager and security department

TECHNICAL SALES & SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE (TOYOTA)

PPG Industries (UK) Ltd. / Birmingham / 2012-2020

To be the primary contact for PPG in client facing areas, ensuring delivery of weekly reports and improving forecasting.

SKILLS

/LANGUAGE/

- Japanese (Native)
- German (Basic)

/PROFESSIONAL/

- Negotiation
- Data Analysis
- Data Management
- Project Management
- Verbal/Written Communication
- Problem Solving/PPS
- Active Listening
- Commodity codes/HS codes
- Risk Assessments
- Process Improvement
- Time Management

/TECHNICAL/

- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft Power Point
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft Project
- VBA
- Power Query
- Adobe Acrobat
- CRM/ClientLink

HARUKA HASHIMOTO

CLIENT ACCOUNT MANAGEMENT

WORK EXPERIENCE - CONTINUED

TECHNICAL SALES & SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE (TOYOTA) - CONTINUED

PPG Industries (UK) Ltd. / Birmingham / 2012-2020

- Boosted the customer experience of a production site audit in Spain by providing language support for a Japanese client
- Organised a well-received customer training workshop at a production site in Italy
- Enhanced product consumption forecast from below target to above 85%
- Improved customer colour approval ratings to above 98%
- Programmed KPI reports using VBA and Power Query to increase productivity by 75%
- Delivered an internal training on repair techniques
- Charted production volume and defect data to report FTR rate weekly, internally and externally
- Presented weekly inventory status and devised action plans for items below
 4 weeks of stock
- Constructed an in-depth process maps to aid product development and process alignment
- Prepared and reviewed monthly KPI to adjust consumption rates and forecast

TECHNICAL SALES & SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE (HONDA)

PPG Industries (UK) Ltd. / Birmingham / 2008-2012

Engage with customers to understand their needs and develop a strong relationship. Undertake daily product inspection and ensure product is maintained within the agreed specification.

- Enter monthly customer build volume forecast and coordinate product replenishment timings
- Briefed senior managements on weekly account KPI, highlighting inventory and quality concerns
- Coordinated analysis of over 10 products and communicated externally on a weekly basis in readiness for an extended plant closure
- Eliminated the storage & delivery costs of third party sourced products by changing transport arrangements
- Improved product forecast from below target to above 70%

RESEARCH PROJECT ASSISTANT

Leicester University / Leicester / 2006-2007

Plan and execute laboratory experiments and analyze results in conjunction with published scientific journals to complete a research project.

 Authored and presented the research article - "Integration of the auditory and the somatosensory information in thedorsal cochlear nucleus"

*References available upon request

EDUCATION

CODING BOOT CAMP FULL STACK FLEX

University of Birmingham
In Progress (Expected Completion
December 2022)

BSC (HONS) 2:1 APPLIED & HUMAN BIOLOGY WITH TRAINING

Aston University 2004-2008

- Cell Biology
- Clinical Microbiology
- Toxicology
- Microbial Pathogenesis
- Mycology
- Food Microbiology

EXTRA

OPERATIONAL EXCELLENCE WORK-OUT & KAISEN FACILITATOR

LinkedIn Online Learning Online, November 2019

SIX SIGMA (GREEN BELT)

LinkedIn Online Learning Online, October 2019

PPG AUTOMOTIVE OEM COATINGS QUALITY RECOGNITION AWARD

PPG Industries (UK) Ltd. Birmingham, 2015

ACOUSTIC OVEREXPOSURE
INCREASES THE EXPRESSION OF
VGLUT-2 MEDIATED PROJECTIONS
FROM THE LATERAL VESTIBULAR
NUCLEUS TO THE DORSAL
COCHLEAR NUCLEUS

PLOS ONE Cambridge, May 2012